orcinternational.com 2019-12-19

# Privacy - ORC International, Inc.

**Regional Policies**

View **[UK Privacy Policy ](https://orcinternational.co.uk/privacy/)**

View[ **UK Respondent Privacy Policy**](https://orcinternational.co.uk/uk-privacy-policy/)

View [ **Australia Privacy Policy**](https://orcinternational.com/australia-privacy-policy/)

**Online Services**

View: **[Online Services Terms and Conditions](https://orcinternational.com/online-terms-and-conditions/)**

**CARAVAN**

View: **[CARAVAN Terms and Conditions](https://orcinternational.com/caravan-terms-conditions/)**

##### **ORC Privacy Policy**

Welcome! At ORC International (“ORC”), consumer privacy is very important to the success of the organization. ORC is a part of the Engine Group of companies that specialize in marketing services and technology.  This privacy policy applies solely to the information collected by ORC through any of its websites or, from time to time, survey participants.  It is with this deep level of dedication to our clients and consumers that we can devote ourselves to managing the use of data across our marketing research product life cycle while focusing on protecting consumer privacy.  It is with this mindset that we can say with confidence that we are proud to be a true innovator in the way people, including ourselves, obtain important information that is relevant to us while respecting consumer privacy.  ORC strictly adheres to applicable privacy laws and conducts its business in accordance with best practices as set forth by the Insights Association (IA) and members of the European Society for Opinion and Marketing Research (ESOMAR).

Our Privacy Policy is aimed to clarify what information ORC collects, and how it utilizes the data on behalf of its clients.  We describe our entire ORC practices for data collection globally on this website as well as how we collect, use, share, and safeguard data collected through and for clients while innovating to provide better information to our clients who utilize such data to improve insights on their businesses and improve products and services.

##### **Contents**

  1. _Short Form Privacy Policy_
  2. _What Does ORC Do?_
  3. _Scope of Privacy Policy_
  4. _Privacy by Design_
  5. _How Does ORC Provide Research Services? _
  6. _ORC May Provide Services on the Web_
  7. _What is a “Cookie” or “Pixel Tag”?_
  8. _Disclosure of Information_
  9. _Data Retention_
  10. _Your Choices_
  11. _Mobile Device Choices_
  12. _Safeguarding Information We Collect and Use_
  13. _Privacy of Children_
  14. _Changes to This Privacy Policy and How to Contact Us_
  15. _Terms & Conditions During Your Visit to the ORC Website_

In this Privacy Policy, we discuss our data use practices in relation to individuals and devices.  Personally Identifiable Information (“PII”) refers to data that is used, or intended to be used, to directly identify a particular individual; Non-PII refers to data that is not linked, or reasonably linkable, to an individual, but is linked or reasonably linkable to a particular computer or device; and De-Identified Data refers to data that is not linkable to either an individual or a device.

##### **Short Form Privacy Policy.**

While we encourage you to read the entire privacy policy, the following summary provides some key information relating to our privacy disclosures and practices.

  * **Information Collection: PII –** We collect PII (i.e., personal data), as defined by the laws or regulations of the country of applicability as described by the Insights Association (IA) and European Society for Opinion and Marketing Research (ESOMAR). For example, PII may be collected should a consumer contact ORC on his/her own initiative or opt-in to register or to participate in a survey.
  * **Information Collection: Non-PII**   The Non-PII we collect may include, as an example, browser types, IP address, domain names, operating systems, language preference, platform type, access dates and times, referring website addresses, browsing, search activity, and online transactions.
  * ****Information Collection: Appended Information**** We may receive information about you from other sources, including publicly available databases or third parties from whom we have purchased data, and combine this data with information we already have about you. This helps us to update, expand and analyze our records, identify new customers, and provide products and services that may be of interest to our clients and consumers. Examples of the types of personal information that may be obtained from public sources or purchased from third parties and combined with information we already have about you, may include: Purchased marketing data about our customers from third parties that is combined with information we already have about you, to create more accurate research results for our clients which leads to better products and services for businesses and consumers.
  * **How Information is Put to Use** We may use your Non-PII for purposes to enhance our services and to more effectively research issues that our clients need help with.
  * **Sharing Your Information** We may share your information with third party service providers with whom we have contracted, ORC and its subsidiaries and affiliates, third party marketing partners, business partners and our clients and publishers, and as expressly provided for herein.
  * **Your Choices** You may regulate the collection and use of Non-PII in your browser, by uninstalling or electing not to install an app, or opting out with the Network Advertising Initiative or Digital Advertising Alliance at either <https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/> or <https://www.aboutads.info/choices/>.
  * **Security** We use reasonable and appropriate security measures to protect your data.
  * **Retention** We retain consumer information no more than is reasonably necessary for research purposes. Aggregate Non-PII data for reporting may be retained for a longer period.
  * **Changes** We may change this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the revised Privacy Policy on the Site along with the date such Privacy Policy was last updated.
  * **Contact Us** If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy please email us at  _[dpo_US@orcinternational.com](mailto:dpo_US@orcinternational.com)_   via mail to Legal Counsel, ORC, 229 West 43rd St., 8th Floor, New York, NY 10036.

##### **What Does ORC Do?**

ORC provides market opinion and social research for clients. Using such gathered information, data analytics and other tools used in the data and behavioral science fields, ORC is able to generate insights which aid clients who may be providers of goods and services, not-for-profit organizations, and governments, in making more informed business decisions.

 As a founding member of the Council of American Survey Research Organizations (CASRO), which in 2016 combined with the Market Research Association to form the Insights Association (IA), and member of the European Society for Opinion and Marketing Research (ESOMAR), we must adhere to rigorous industry standards which exist in part to safeguard your privacy and the security of your personal information.

Our experiences have helped us forge our business around one central belief:  _It is possible to provide everyone with the privacy they deserve, while giving them access to positive-sum innovation that is valuable to society in the form of better services through better research that is both relevant to consumers and economically viable for organizations and individuals._

##### **Scope of Privacy Policy.**

This Privacy Policy applies to ORC and not to any of our third party partners. We discuss the collection and use purposes of data and the method of collection and use of PII and Non-Personally Identifiable Information (“Non-PII”) gathered by us.  It also does not apply to the privacy practices of any of our research clients.

##### **Privacy by Design.**

Our foundation of building a strong privacy framework at ORC follows an internal framework of Privacy by Design. We integrate privacy in strategy, research, surveys, and more. Our internal procedures include privacy protection early and often, proactively aligning our data use practices in a manner that maximizes the innovative benefits of our services in the 21st Century while keeping consumer privacy at the forefront of our business practices and building infrastructure that is effective to guard the data we are entrusted with. We can protect consumer privacy AND provide relevant services in the research sector, which benefits everyone involved, especially clients and consumers. Ensuring the protection of privacy throughout the entire lifecycle of the data is of the utmost importance and ORC is careful to protect privacy as data is collected, used, and destroyed responsibly.

ORC has developed a strong privacy foundation and has a company culture aimed at data minimization, pseudonymization and adequate data encryption and security.

##### **How Does ORC Provide Research Services?**

We partner with businesses whose privacy policies allow them to share information about their customers and/or inquirers as well as information about a consumer’s interests as inferred from their web browser. This information may include the date and time of a visit to their store, website or mobile application, or allow us to visit their stores to obtain consent from their customers to do surveys or send them online through traditional ad space or by email. The information allows us to research and provide our clients more about the things consumers are interested in, allowing businesses to improve their products or services as a result.

##### **How does ORC use the Web to support its research?**

When a consumer engages with an online survey from us, we will obtain consent to utilize a “cookie” or “pixel tag” to be placed on the consumer’s machine by a third party partner that may collect device identifiers like iOS and Android Unique Identification Number (UID). Information collected from a cookie, UID, or pixel tag are not linked to PII. No PII is transferred in the cookie, UID or pixel tag to a third party. A third party only knows that consumer by a pseudonymous ID, so that we can tailor more relevant messaging to the consumer and help provide more relevant information to them.

##### **What is a “Cookie” or “Pixel Tag”?**

A cookie is an industry-standard small data file placed on a consumer’s computer. Cookies allow marketers to “remember you” when you return to their website. Again, no PII is transferred in the ORC cookie to a third party. This website and associated surveys may contain, in addition to ORC cookies, other third party cookies that assist us in supplying information that will make it easier for you to navigate on our site.  A pixel tag (also commonly known as a web beacon or clear gif) is an industry-standard, often transparent graphic image usually no larger than a 1×1 pixel that is placed in a website or e-mail.

Pixel tags are used by ORC to transfer relevant Non-PII data from this website or a client’s website to third parties associated with us for the purpose of providing additional research and relevant information for clients to use to make their customer’s online experience more relevant. Cookies are used by ORC to link this Non-PII data to non-identified unique users. Pixel tags and cookies may also be used to link additional Non-PII information provided by a third party.

##### **Disclosure of Information.**

We may disclose proprietary, Non-PII information to our clients for reporting purposes, and we may share aggregated information as well as certain PII such as name, address, email address and transactions with other third parties for analytical and research purposes. ORC may also need to disclose information if (1) we believe that there has been a violation of the law, of your rights, or of our rights, (2) to respond to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements, or in connection with an investigation on matters related to public safety, as permitted by law, or otherwise as required by law, and (3) if our company or substantially all of its assets are acquired.

##### **Data Retention.**

ORC retains data it uses for research purposes for periods determined by our clients, after which the information is removed and discarded.  If you have contacted us or provided PII to ORC to be contacted or joined our mailing list, we will retain your information for as long as you’re active or as needed to provide you with information. 

##### **Your Choices.**

Upon request, ORC will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information.  You may access, correct, or request deletion of your PII by contacting us at  _[dpo_US@orcinternational.com](mailto:dpo_US@orcinternational.com)_.  We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. In order to help us to respond promptly to your enquiry or request, please include as much information as you can in your communication with us – such as the reason you believe we hold any of your data, and any other supporting information such as a particular survey or focus group you took part in, or the title of any email you may have received, or the phone number you may have received a call from. 

We hope that after reading through this Privacy Policy that you accept that ORC is collecting and using data responsibly, and that the cumulative benefits of our work are beneficial to improving the lives of people around the world. In cases where we use third parties to provide interest based surveys or advertisements, you may wish to use browser settings to modify your preferences. At ORC our goal is to offer a harmonized online experience with whatever browser you use. Most browsers accept cookies by default but in certain cases, like Safari, our cookies are blocked by default by the browser settings (and potentially without your knowledge). In cases where you interact with our service and want to experience our personalized ads your browser settings may nonetheless be configured to block certain third party cookies.

ORC utilizes the services of third parties that are a member of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) and adheres to its Codes of Conduct. You can learn more about the NAI by visiting [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). NAI offers an online [opt-out](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) platform to allow customers to express their choices and provides general information related to Interest Based Advertising.

ORC may have third parties place survey requests on websites that are part of the Google Display Network. Based on your visits to these websites, Google uses an advertising cookie (from DoubleClick) to associate your browser with interest and demographic categories. Google then uses these categories for IBA on these websites. To learn more about this and your choices from Google, please [click here.](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en) 

We partner with a third party to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partners may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interest. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising in general, [click here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/), or if located in the European Union [click here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). Please note you will continue to receive generic ads.

Some web browsers may also give you the ability to enable a “do not track” setting. This setting sends a special signal to the websites you encounter while web browsing. This “do not track” signal is different from disabling certain forms of tracking by declining cookies in your browser settings, as browsers with the “do not track” setting enabled still have the ability to accept cookies. Most advertising exchanges and networks do not respond to web browser “do not track” signals at this time. If we do so in the future, we will describe how we do so in this Privacy Statement. For more information about “do not track,” visit [www.allaboutdnt.org](http://www.allaboutdnt.org/).  You may control the collection and use of Non-PII in your browser by uninstalling or electing not to install an app, or through the [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/) and [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) choice pages.

##### **Mobile Device Choices.**

For mobile websites, you can delete our cookie via the browser settings. For mobile apps, you can typically limit ad tracking within the settings function. On most Android devices, in the “Ads” menu, you can opt out of receiving IBA, or reset your advertising ID. On most Apple iOS devices, you can use the Ad Tracking settings to limit receipt of IBA or reset your device’s Advertising Identifier. Please note that your experience may be different depending on your individual device and service. In addition to using the options above, you may also uninstall the application from your device.  If you download a mobile application, it may use advertising to fund its development and maintenance of its software in iOS and Android.  In situations involving applications, if you do not want to receive IBA you will need to remove those applications from your device.

##### **Safeguarding Information We Collect and Use.**

The security of your information is important to us. We have implemented appropriate security measures to protect the information in our care, both during transmission and once we receive it. We take reasonable physical and technical security measures to protect our data from unauthorized access, as well as unauthorized disclosure.

##### **Privacy of Children.**

We are committed to protecting the privacy of children. Neither ORC’s website nor ORC online activities with its clients are intended or designed to knowingly attract children under the age of 13.

##### **Changes to This Privacy Policy**

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. When we do, we will post the change(s) on our website.  If we made a material change, we will provide prominent notice on this site in the future. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. 

##### **Terms & Conditions During Your Visit to the ORC Website**

The place of performance for this website is New York.  ORC makes no representation that materials at this site are appropriate or available for use outside of the United States and access to them from territories where their contents are illegal is prohibited.  You are responsible for compliance with local laws in relation to the use of this site outside the United States.  If you publish a blog, that blog may be shared with third parties by other visitors to this website.  The use of this site does not establish any joint venture, partnership, employment, or agency relationship between you and ORC.  The Choice of Law is Illinois. You hereby consent to the jurisdiction and venue in the state and federal courts in Chicago, Illinois.  Please be aware that ORC may provide links to other websites, which if you click on them may collect personal information about you.  The information practices of those third party websites linked to ORC are not covered by this Privacy Statement.

Headings are for reference purposes only and in no way define, limit, construe or describe the scope or extent of such section. As a visitor to this website, YOU UNDERSTAND AND CONSENT THAT ANY DISPUTE CONCERNING PRIVACY IS SUBJECT TO THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND APPLICABLE SITE TERMS AND CONDITIONS. You also agree that you have provided notice to, and obtained consent from, any third party individuals whose information you supply to us with regard to: (a) the purposes for which such third party’s information has been collected; (b) the intended recipients or categories of recipients of the third party’s information; (c) which of the third party’s data are obligatory and which data, if any, are voluntary; and (d) how the third party can access and, if necessary, rectify the data held about them. It is the express wish of the parties that the Privacy Policy and all related documents have been drawn up in the English language and that the English version of this Privacy Policy shall be the sole version used in interpreting and enforcing this Privacy Policy.

Your use of this website constitutes agreement to indemnify ORC and affiliated entities and hold them harmless from any and all claims and expenses, including attorney’s fees, arising from your use of the website.

YOU AGREE THAT OUR LIABILITY FOR ANY BREACH OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY SHALL BE LIMITED TO THE VALUE OF THE TRANSACTIONS OR SERVICES PROVIDED TO YOU BY US TO THE EXTENT SUCH CLAIM IS NOT OTHERWISE BARRED BY OUR TERMS AND CONDITIONS.
